ANDALUCIA, SPAIN
The Inquisition has finally
delivered Spain to the Templars.
Sultan Muhammad and his
people still hold out in Granada.
But if his son,
the prince, is captured,
he will surrender the city
and the Apple of Eden.
Do you, Aguilar de Nerha,
swear to honor our order
in the fight for freedom?
To defend mankind
against Templars' tyranny,
and preserve free will?
I swear.
If the Apple falls
into their hands,
the Templars will destroy
everything that stands in their way.
Protest, dissent, our right
to think for ourselves.
Swear to me that you
will sacrifice your life
and lives of everyone
here to keep it from them.
Yes, Mentor.
Our lives are nothing.
The Apple is everything.
The spirit of the Eagle,
will watch over the future.
Where other men blindly
follow the truth,
remember, nothing is true.
Where other men are
limited by morality or law,
remember,
everything is permitted.
We work in the darkness
to serve the light.
We are Assassins.
It's the prince.
Which household
harbored the boy?
Only me.
Nobody else knew.
Nobody.
Hang his family
and make him watch.
Burn the whole village.
With the prince of Granada
as captive, his father, sultan,
will surrender his
rebellious city,
the last safe haven
for the infidels.
God will punish his
people's heresy.
Finally Spain will be
under one Templar rule.
Stay with the memory, Cal.
Aguilar! The boy, Aguilar!
The boy!
Aguilar, the boy!
Crazy for crying...
Staying in synch-void
could be dangerous.
And I'm crazy for loving you...
Soon they will march on Granada.
Sultan Muhammad is weak.
He'll surrender the Apple
and betray the
Creed to save the prince.
The love makes us weak.
Gladly I'll sacrifice
my flesh and blood,
for survival of the Creed.
When I die today,
don't waste your tears for me.
The Lord spoke.
And he said:
"If a man abide not in me
he is cast into the fire
and he is burned!"
For decades,
you have lived in
the world torn apart
by religious discord.
But soon, thanks to God
and Inquisition
we will purge this disease!
The sinners before you,
sought to defend the
heretic prince of Granada,
the last heathen stronghold
in our holy war.
So today,
before our king and queen
I swear we shall
wash ourselves clean,
in the holy fire of God!
Behold...
God's will!
You will watch your mentor burn
and then you will die the slowest.
Give glory to the future.
Not to us.
Damned heretics!
Don't let them escape!
For the Creed.
Our own lives...
What matters is what
we leave behind.
Sultan...
Surrender the Apple.
Your Assassin protectors are gone.
The Creed is finished.
My son.
Here lies the seed
of man's first disobedience,
of free will itself.
Thanks to the Apple of Eden,
the known world
shall be ushered into a new age.
One of peace,
in which all the warring
populations of mankind
shall bow in perfect obedience
to our one templar rule.
The Apple.
Give it to him.
Now.
For the Creed.
Go!
Forgive me.
It's over!
Assassin!
The Assassins died for it.
Protect it with your life.
I am a friend of the Creed.
Take it to your grave.
I swear.